<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development :: Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/development/index.html</link><description>Development Resources for contributing to and developing Kure.
Development Guide - Setting up a development environment, running tests, and contributing GitHub Workflows - CI/CD pipeline documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Development Guide</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/development/guide/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/development/guide/index.html</guid><description>Development Guide This guide covers development workflows and tooling for the Kure project.
Quick Start # Get help with all available commands make help # Run all standard development tasks make all # Quick development cycle make check Development Workflow 1. Initial Setup # Install dependencies make deps # Install development tools make tools 2. Development Cycle # Format code make fmt # Run quick checks (lint, vet, short tests) make check # Run all tests make test # Run tests with coverage make test-coverage 3. Building # Build all executables make build # Build specific executable make build-kure make build-kurel make build-demo # Build with race detection for debugging make build-race 4. Testing # Run all tests make test # Run tests with verbose output make test-verbose # Run tests with race detection make test-race # Run only short tests (good for quick feedback) make test-short # Run tests with coverage report make test-coverage # Run benchmark tests make test-benchmark # Run integration tests (when available) make test-integration 5. Code Quality # Run all linting make lint # Format code make fmt # Run go vet make vet # Tidy modules make tidy # Run Qodana static analysis (requires Docker) make qodana 6. Demo and Examples # Run comprehensive demo make demo # Run GVK generators demo make demo-gvk # Generate all examples (alias for demo) make examples 7. Package Operations # Build a kurel package make kurel-build PACKAGE_PATH=path/to/package # Show package information make kurel-info PACKAGE_PATH=path/to/package Pre-commit Workflow Before committing changes, run:</description></item><item><title>GitHub Workflows</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/development/github-workflows/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/development/github-workflows/index.html</guid><description>GitHub Workflows Documentation This document provides an overview of all GitHub Actions workflows used in the kure project.
Last Updated: 2026-01-28
Workflow Summary Workflow File Triggers Purpose CI ci.yml push, PR, schedule, manual Comprehensive testing, linting, building, security Release release.yml version tags GoReleaser-based release with CI validation CI Workflow File: .github/workflows/ci.yml Name: CI
Triggers Push to: main, develop, release/* Pull requests to: main, develop Schedule: 4am UTC daily (catch external changes) Manual dispatch Concurrency Uses github.sha to avoid duplicate runs:</description></item></channel></rss>