<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/index.html</link><description>Kure: Type-Safe Kubernetes Resource Generation Warning Work in Progress: Kure is currently under active development (v0.1.0-alpha.2). APIs and features are subject to change. Kure is a Go library for programmatically building Kubernetes resources, designed for GitOps workflows with FluxCD. Instead of complex templating engines, Kure provides strongly-typed, composable resource generation in native Go.
Why Kure? Building Kubernetes manifests for GitOps can be challenging:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/getting-started/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/getting-started/index.html</guid><description>Getting Started with Kure Kure is primarily a Go library. You can also install its CLI tools for package management and code generation.
Using as a Library Add Kure to your Go project:
go get github.com/go-kure/kure Then import the packages you need:
import ( "github.com/go-kure/kure/pkg/stack" "github.com/go-kure/kure/pkg/kubernetes/fluxcd" "github.com/go-kure/kure/pkg/io" ) Installing CLI Tools # kure — main CLI for resource generation go install github.com/go-kure/kure/cmd/kure@latest # kurel — package system for reusable application bundles go install github.com/go-kure/kure/cmd/kurel@latest Verify the installation:</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/index.html</guid><description>Concepts Understand the ideas behind Kure’s design.
Architecture - System architecture and component overview Domain Model - The Cluster, Node, Bundle, Application hierarchy Design Philosophy - Type-safe builders, no templating, GitOps-native</description></item><item><title>Guides</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/guides/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/guides/index.html</guid><description>Guides Step-by-step guides for common Kure workflows.
Using Kure as a Library - Import paths, creating resources, generating YAML Generating Flux Manifests - End-to-end cluster definition to disk Working with Generators - The GVK system and application generators Patching Resources - JSONPath patching and TOML patch format Building Kurel Packages - Creating reusable application packages</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.html</guid><description>Examples Practical examples of using Kure to generate Kubernetes configurations.
Mounted Examples These examples include full documentation:
Patches - Declarative patching with TOML and YAML formats Generators - Resource generation using the GVK system Kurel Frigate - Building a complete kurel package Validation - Resource validation patterns Additional Examples These examples are available in the examples/ directory on GitHub:
App Workloads (examples/appworkloads/) - Application workload generation Bootstrap (examples/bootstrap/) - Flux bootstrap configuration Clusters (examples/clusters/) - Multi-cluster definitions Multi-OCI (examples/multi-oci/) - Multi-source OCI deployments</description></item><item><title>CLI Reference</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/cli-reference/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/cli-reference/index.html</guid><description>CLI Reference Kure provides two command-line tools.
kure The main CLI for Kubernetes resource generation.
kure [command] [flags] Commands Command Description generate Generate Kubernetes resources from configuration patch Apply patches to existing manifests validate Validate resource configurations config Manage kure configuration version Print version information completion Generate shell completion scripts kurel The package system CLI for building and managing reusable application packages.
kurel [command] [flags] Commands Command Description build Build Kubernetes manifests from a kurel package validate Validate kurel package structure and configuration info Show package information schema Schema generation and validation commands config Manage kurel configuration version Print version information completion Generate shell completion scripts kurel build kurel build &lt;package&gt; [flags] Flag Description -o, --output Output path (default: stdout) --values Values file for parameter overrides -p, --patch Enable specific patches --format Output format: yaml, json (default: yaml) --kind Filter by resource kind --name Filter by resource name --add-label Add labels to all resources kurel validate kurel validate &lt;package&gt; [flags] Flag Description --values Values file for validation --schema Custom schema file --json Output validation results as JSON kurel info kurel info &lt;package&gt; [flags] Flag Description -o, --output Output format: text, yaml, json (default: text) --all Show all details including resource content Global Flags Both tools support:</description></item><item><title>API Reference</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/api-reference/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/api-reference/index.html</guid><description>API Reference Kure’s public API is organized into focused packages. Each package README below is auto-synced from the source code.
For full Go API documentation, see pkg.go.dev/github.com/go-kure/kure .
Core Domain Package Description Reference Stack Cluster, Node, Bundle, Application domain model pkg.go.dev Flux Engine FluxCD workflow implementation pkg.go.dev Generators Application generator system (GVK) pkg.go.dev Layout Engine Manifest directory organization pkg.go.dev Package System Package Description Reference Launcher Kurel package loading, building, validation pkg.go.dev Resource Operations Package Description Reference Patch JSONPath-based declarative patching pkg.go.dev IO YAML/JSON serialization and resource printing pkg.go.dev Kubernetes Builders Core K8s resource constructors (GVK, HPA, PDB) pkg.go.dev FluxCD Builders Low-level Flux resource constructors pkg.go.dev Utilities Package Description Reference Errors Structured error types pkg.go.dev CLI Utilities Factory, IOStreams, Printer pkg.go.dev Logger Structured logging pkg.go.dev Compatibility Compatibility Matrix - Supported Kubernetes and dependency versions ArgoCD ArgoCD support exists at pkg/stack/argocd/ but is not yet production-ready. It is not featured in guides or examples. The Flux workflow is the primary supported GitOps integration.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/changelog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/changelog/index.html</guid><description>Changelog Track changes across Kure releases.
Releases - Version history and release notes</description></item><item><title>Contributing</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/contributing/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/contributing/index.html</guid><description>Contributing Resources for contributing to Kure.
Development Guide - Setup, testing, code quality, and CI/CD workflows GitHub Workflows - CI/CD pipeline documentation Quick Start # Clone the repository git clone https://github.com/go-kure/kure.git cd kure # Install tools make tools # Run checks make check # Run full pre-commit validation make precommit Branch Workflow main is protected. Create a feature branch:
git checkout -b feat/my-feature main # make changes git push -u origin feat/my-feature gh pr create Required CI checks: lint, test, build.</description></item></channel></rss>