<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/index.html</link><description>Kure: Type-Safe Kubernetes Resource Generation Warning Work in Progress: Kure is currently under active development and has not been released yet. APIs and features are subject to change. Kure is a powerful Go library for programmatically building Kubernetes resources, designed specifically for GitOps workflows. Say goodbye to complex templating engines and hello to strongly-typed, composable resource generation.
Why Kure? Building Kubernetes manifests for GitOps can be challenging:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/overview/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/overview/index.html</guid><description>Overview Kure is a Go library and CLI toolset for programmatic Kubernetes resource generation, designed for GitOps workflows with Flux and ArgoCD.
Explore the Project README for a comprehensive introduction.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/getting-started/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/getting-started/index.html</guid><description>Getting Started with Kure This section helps you get up and running with Kure quickly.
Installation Install the Kure CLI tools using Go:
go install github.com/go-kure/kure/cmd/kure@latest go install github.com/go-kure/kure/cmd/kurel@latest Verify the installation:
kure version kurel version Next Steps Follow the Quickstart guide Explore the Packages documentation Read the Architecture overview Try the Examples</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/index.html</guid><description>Architecture Deep dive into Kure’s design and architecture.
Architecture Details - Core architecture and design principles Plugin Architecture - Plugin system design UX Design - User experience design decisions</description></item><item><title>Packages</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/packages/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/packages/index.html</guid><description>Kure Packages Explore the core packages that make up the Kure library. Each package provides specific functionality for building and managing Kubernetes resources.
Core Packages Launcher The launcher package provides a package system for creating reusable, customizable Kubernetes applications without the complexity of templating engines. It uses a declarative patch-based approach to customize base Kubernetes manifests.
Patch The patch package implements a JSONPath-based declarative patching system. It allows you to modify Kubernetes resources using a simple, powerful patch language that maintains YAML structure and comments.</description></item><item><title>Examples</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.html</guid><description>Examples Explore practical examples of using Kure to generate Kubernetes configurations.
Patches - Declarative patching examples Generators - Resource generation examples Kurel Frigate - Building a kurel package Validation - Resource validation examples</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/reference/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/reference/index.html</guid><description>Reference API Documentation Full Go API documentation is available on pkg.go.dev:
github.com/go-kure/kure — Root module pkg/launcher — Launcher package system pkg/patch — JSONPath patching pkg/stack — Stack data model pkg/stack/layout — Directory layout generation pkg/stack/generators — Resource generators pkg/io — YAML I/O and resource printing pkg/errors — Structured error types pkg/cli — CLI utilities pkg/kubernetes/fluxcd — FluxCD resource builders Additional References Compatibility Matrix - Supported tool and dependency versions</description></item><item><title>Development</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/development/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/development/index.html</guid><description>Development Resources for contributing to and developing Kure.
Development Guide - Setting up a development environment, running tests, and contributing GitHub Workflows - CI/CD pipeline documentation</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/changelog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/changelog/index.html</guid><description>Changelog Track changes across Kure releases.
Releases - Version history and release notes</description></item></channel></rss>