<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Architecture :: Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/index.html</link><description>Architecture Deep dive into Kure’s design and architecture.
Architecture Details - Core architecture and design principles Plugin Architecture - Plugin system design UX Design - User experience design decisions</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architecture Details</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/details/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/details/index.html</guid><description>Kure Architecture Documentation Version: 2.0.0
Date: August 2025
Status: Complete
Executive Summary Kure is a Go library for programmatically building Kubernetes resources used by GitOps tools (Flux, cert-manager, MetalLB, External Secrets). The library emphasizes strongly-typed object construction over templating engines, providing a composable, type-safe approach to generating Kubernetes manifests.
Key Architectural Achievements:
Domain-Driven Design: Hierarchical cluster model with clear boundaries Interface Segregation: Split monolithic workflow interfaces into focused components Type Safety: Strong typing throughout with comprehensive validation GitOps Agnostic: Support for multiple GitOps tools through pluggable workflows Declarative Patching: JSONPath-based patching system with structure preservation The architecture supports complex Kubernetes cluster configurations while maintaining simplicity and extensibility through clean separation of concerns and well-defined interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Plugin Architecture</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/plugin-design/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/plugin-design/index.html</guid><description>Plugin Architecture Design for Kure Overview This document outlines the design for implementing a plugin architecture that allows external generators to extend Kure’s capabilities. The plugin system would enable users to create custom generators for specific needs (Terraform, Pulumi, custom CRDs, etc.) while maintaining type safety and security.
Current Generator Architecture Kure currently uses a static registration system where generators implement the ApplicationConfig interface:
type ApplicationConfig interface { Generate(*Application) ([]*client.Object, error) } Built-in generators like AppWorkload and FluxHelm register themselves via init() functions using the GVK (Group, Version, Kind) system:</description></item><item><title>UX Design</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/ux-design/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/architecture/ux-design/index.html</guid><description>Kure End User Experience Design Document Version: 1.0
Date: August 2025
Status: Design Specification
Executive Summary This document outlines a comprehensive user experience strategy for Kure, a Go library for programmatically building Kubernetes resources for GitOps workflows. The design focuses on creating multiple interaction modalities that serve different user types while maintaining Kure’s core strengths of type safety, composability, and GitOps compatibility.
Key Design Principles:
Progressive Complexity: Simple defaults with expert-level customization Multi-Modal Interaction: Visual, programmatic, and hybrid approaches Type-Safe Configuration: Leveraging Kure’s existing validation and GVK system GitOps Native: Seamless integration with Flux and ArgoCD workflows Table of Contents User Research &amp; Personas Current State Analysis Vision &amp; Design Principles User Journey Maps Multi-Modal Interface Design Configuration Management System Implementation Roadmap Success Metrics User Research &amp; Personas Primary User Personas 1. Platform Engineer (Sarah) Role: Senior Platform Engineer at mid-size tech company Experience: 5+ years Kubernetes, familiar with GitOps concepts Goals: Standardize cluster configurations, reduce operational overhead Pain Points: Complex YAML management, ensuring consistency across environments Preferred Interaction: Programmatic APIs with visual validation 2. DevOps Beginner (Mike) Role: Junior DevOps Engineer, transitioning from traditional ops Experience: 1 year Kubernetes, new to GitOps Goals: Learn best practices, avoid configuration mistakes Pain Points: Overwhelmed by Kubernetes complexity, unclear dependencies Preferred Interaction: Guided workflows with explanations 3. Solutions Architect (Alex) Role: Technical lead designing multi-cluster architectures Experience: 8+ years infrastructure, deep Kubernetes knowledge Goals: Design scalable, maintainable cluster architectures Pain Points: Visualizing complex dependencies, communicating designs to teams Preferred Interaction: Visual modeling with code generation 4. Development Team Lead (Jordan) Role: Engineering manager overseeing application deployment Experience: 3 years Kubernetes, focused on application concerns Goals: Self-service application deployment, consistent configurations Pain Points: Waiting for platform team, inconsistent environments Preferred Interaction: Template-based configuration with customization User Needs Analysis User Type Primary Need Secondary Need Success Criteria Platform Engineer Standardization &amp; Automation Visual Validation Reduced config drift, faster onboarding DevOps Beginner Learning &amp; Guidance Error Prevention Successful deployments, increased confidence Solutions Architect Design &amp; Communication Code Generation Clear architecture docs, team alignment Development Team Lead Self-Service &amp; Consistency Template Management Faster deployments, reduced dependencies Current State Analysis Existing Interaction Model Currently, users interact with Kure through direct Go code:</description></item></channel></rss>