<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Concepts :: Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/index.html</link><description>Concepts Understand the ideas behind Kure’s design.
Architecture - System architecture and component overview Domain Model - The Cluster, Node, Bundle, Application hierarchy Design Philosophy - Type-safe builders, no templating, GitOps-native</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/architecture/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/architecture/index.html</guid><description>Kure Architecture Documentation Version: 2.0.0
Date: August 2025
Status: Complete
Executive Summary Kure is a Go library for programmatically building Kubernetes resources used by GitOps tools (Flux, cert-manager, MetalLB, External Secrets). The library emphasizes strongly-typed object construction over templating engines, providing a composable, type-safe approach to generating Kubernetes manifests.
Key Architectural Achievements:
Domain-Driven Design: Hierarchical cluster model with clear boundaries Interface Segregation: Split monolithic workflow interfaces into focused components Type Safety: Strong typing throughout with comprehensive validation GitOps Agnostic: Support for multiple GitOps tools through pluggable workflows Declarative Patching: JSONPath-based patching system with structure preservation The architecture supports complex Kubernetes cluster configurations while maintaining simplicity and extensibility through clean separation of concerns and well-defined interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Domain Model</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/domain-model/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/domain-model/index.html</guid><description>Domain Model Kure models Kubernetes infrastructure as a four-level hierarchy. Each level maps to a concept in GitOps deployment workflows.
The Hierarchy Cluster └── Node (tree structure) └── Bundle (deployment unit) └── Application (workload) Cluster The root of the hierarchy, representing a target Kubernetes cluster. A cluster has a name, a tree of nodes, and GitOps configuration specifying which workflow engine to use (Flux or ArgoCD).
Node An organizational grouping within a cluster. Nodes form a tree structure — for example, a cluster might have top-level nodes for infrastructure and applications, each with child nodes for specific concerns.</description></item><item><title>Design Philosophy</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/design-philosophy/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/concepts/design-philosophy/index.html</guid><description>Design Philosophy Kure is built on a few core principles that guide its design and API choices.
Type-Safe Builders Over Templating Traditional Kubernetes tooling relies on string-based templating (Helm, Kustomize overlays, Jsonnet). This creates a class of errors that only surface at deploy time — typos in YAML paths, type mismatches, missing fields.
Kure uses Go’s type system instead:
// Compile-time checked — typos and type errors are caught by the compiler ks := fluxcd.Kustomization(&amp;fluxcd.KustomizationConfig{ Name: "my-app", Namespace: "flux-system", Path: "./clusters/production/apps", Interval: "10m", Prune: true, }) If you misspell a field name, the Go compiler tells you immediately.</description></item></channel></rss>