<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Examples :: Go Kure</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.html</link><description>Examples Explore practical examples of using Kure to generate Kubernetes configurations.
Patches - Declarative patching examples Generators - Resource generation examples Kurel Frigate - Building a kurel package Validation - Resource validation examples</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.gokure.dev/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Patches</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/patches/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/patches/index.html</guid><description>Kure Patch Module Examples (TOML Format) This directory demonstrates the new TOML-style patch system with cert-manager as an example.
Files cert-manager-simple.yaml - Base cert-manager resources (simplified) resources.kpatch - Resource limits using TOML container selectors ingress.kpatch - Service configuration with port selectors security.kpatch - Security contexts with deployment targeting advanced.kpatch - Complex selectors and variable substitution Running the Demo go run ./cmd/demo -patches TOML Patch Format The patch files now use TOML-style headers for precise resource targeting:</description></item><item><title>Generators</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/generators/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/generators/index.html</guid><description>Generator Examples This directory contains examples of the GVK-based generator system for Kure.
Overview Kure uses a Group, Version, Kind (GVK) pattern similar to Kubernetes for identifying generator types. Each generator:
Has a unique GVK identifier Implements the ApplicationConfig interface Can generate specific types of Kubernetes resources Available Generators AppWorkload (generators.gokure.dev/v1alpha1) Creates standard Kubernetes workloads (Deployments, StatefulSets, DaemonSets) with associated resources.
Example: appworkload.yaml This example creates:
A Deployment with 3 replicas A LoadBalancer Service An Ingress resource Proper resource limits and volume mounts FluxHelm (generators.gokure.dev/v1alpha1) Creates Flux HelmRelease resources with their source configurations.</description></item><item><title>Kurel Frigate</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/kurel-frigate/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/kurel-frigate/index.html</guid><description>Frigate Kurel Package This is a Kurel package for deploying Frigate , a complete and local NVR designed for Home Assistant with AI object detection.
Overview Frigate is a complete and local NVR designed for Home Assistant with AI object detection. It uses OpenCV and Tensorflow to perform realtime object detection locally for IP cameras.
Prerequisites Kubernetes cluster Coral USB TPU device (for hardware acceleration) Node labeled with coral-usb=true where the Coral USB is attached MQTT broker (for Home Assistant integration) Storage provisioner for persistent volumes cert-manager (for TLS certificates) Installation Basic Installation kurel build examples/kurel/frigate | kubectl apply -f - Installation with Custom Values Create a values file my-values.yaml: app: namespace: my-frigate image: tag: 0.13.0 service: loadBalancerIP: 10.0.0.100 ingress: hostname: frigate.mydomain.com storage: size: 200Gi Build and deploy: kurel build examples/kurel/frigate --values my-values.yaml | kubectl apply -f - Using Patches Apply environment-specific patches:</description></item><item><title>Validation</title><link>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/validation/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.gokure.dev/examples/validation/index.html</guid><description>Validation Examples This directory contains examples demonstrating Kure’s built-in validation features.
Bundle Interval Validation File: bundle-intervals.yaml
Demonstrates proper configuration of time interval fields in Bundle resources:
Valid Examples: Recommended patterns and edge cases Invalid Examples: Common mistakes and validation errors (commented out) Error Messages: Examples of validation error output Key Validation Rules Format: Go time.Duration syntax (1s, 5m, 1h, 1h30m) Range: 1 second minimum, 24 hours maximum Fields: interval, timeout, retryInterval Best Practices Reconciliation: Use 5m to 30m for most applications Timeouts: Set 2-3x longer than expected deployment time Retry Intervals: Use 1m to 5m for faster failure recovery Production: Avoid very short intervals (&lt;1m) to reduce API load Testing Validation To test validation with these examples:</description></item></channel></rss>